Just one place... just one place...
tatta hitotsu tatta hitotsu no...
Just one of me... just one of me...
tatta hitori tatta hitori no...
I'm right here.
watashi wa koko
With a chest made of rubble, I can't even breathe.
gareki no mune iki mo dekinai
The rain starts to fall, like a slumbering cry.
furidasu ame nemuru you ni cry
What flower should I decorate myself with
kono sekai o ikinuku no naraba
To stay alive in this world?
donna hana o kazareba ii no?
I want to believe, but still can't manage it...
shinjitai kuse ni shinjirarezu ni
My powerless and pointless self
muryoku de muimi na jibun ga
Still embraces my heart.
soredemo kokoro de idakun da
I can hear a voice calling to me, saying, "Come this way!"
"kocchi e oide" to koe ga kikoeru
A limitless and reckless tomorrow
mugen de mubou na ashita ga
Will still be waiting for me somewhere.
soredemo dokoka de matsu kara
Just one place... just one place...
tatta hitotsu tatta hitotsu no...
Just one of me... just one of me...
tatta hitori tatta hitori no...
I'm right here.
watashi wa koko
Hatori Chise
You're not going to regret this later, are you?
（セス）後悔しませんね？
（チセ）はい
I won't.
Hatori Chise
（セス）これで契約は成立です
With that, the contract is complete.
Hatori Chise-san.
羽鳥智世(はとりちせ)さん
（セス）息苦しくはありませんか？
Can you breathe all right?
（セス）行きましょうか
Let's go.
I'd heard rumors, but I've never seen one before.
（客Ｂ）
うわさには聞いていたが
初めて見たな
There are things that are neither human nor inanimate.
（チセ）
人間や物のほかに
人間じゃないものがいる…
いつも見ているヤツらと違う
They're different from the ones that I always see.
こういうヤツらもいるんだ
I never knew things like this existed.
（チセ）
何でもいい
I don't care.
ただ 帰れる場所が欲しい
I just want somewhere to go home to.
This is the product you've all been waiting for.
（競売人）
こちらが皆様お待ちかねの品
A rare item, even among our current offerings.
今回 出品された商品の中でも
大変 希少なものです
Starting at 500,000.
（競売人）では 50から
（客Ａ）110！
1,100,000!
（客Ｂ）150
1,500,000!
（客Ｃ）180！
1,800,000!
（客Ｂ）200
2,000,000!
（客Ｄ）おい あれを見ろ
Look there.
Why is he here?
（客Ｅ）なんで こんな所に？
（客Ｆ）225！
2,250,000!
（客Ｄ）
あいつは人嫌いという話だったが…
I thought he hated being around people.
2,250,000!
（競売人）225！
ほかに どなたか
いらっしゃいませんか？
Anyone else?
Sir...
（競売人）お客様…
5,000,000.
（エリアス）500
（エリアス）決めた
It's decided.
僕の…
I will make you my apprentice.
弟子にする
What's the deal with that creep?
（アシスタント）
なんだ？ あの不気味な野郎は
Dunno.
応接室の用意を
Prepare a reception room.
Wait...
We will be receiving five million pounds.
（セス）
では こちら
500万ポンドのお支払いですね
Who is he, to want to spend so much money on me?
（チセ）
私なんかに あんな金額を…
Age, fifteen.
Ethnicity, Japanese.
このヒトは何なんだろう？
She's docile, so she should be easy to discipline.
（セス）
攻撃的ではありませんから
しつけは簡単でしょう
まさか あなたが この競りに
顔を出すとは思いませんでした
I never thought I'd see you at this auction.
しかし ルールを
守っていただかないと困りますよ
However, we must ask you to follow the rules.
いきなり舞台に…
Please don't wander onto the stage—
（エリアス）
小言も世間話もいらないよ
I don't need your lecturing nor small talk.
You, come.
君 おいで
You don't need to keep your head down.
うつむかなくていいよ
背筋を伸ばして
しっかり前を見るんだ
Stand tall, and look forward.
いいね？
Understood?
（チセ）はい
Yes.
（エリアス）控え室を借りるよ
I'll be borrowing your lobby.
By all means.
（セス）どうぞ
What is he, a monster?
（アシスタント）化け物か？
He'll hear you.
聞こえますよ
口を慎みなさい
Be quiet.
He's neither a conman nor a sorcerer.
あれは詐欺師でも魔術師でもない
He's the real deal, a rarity in recent times.
今どき珍しい 本物ですよ
I can't believe we let him have that.
（客Ｆ）
しかし 惜しいものを
競り落とされてしまったな
（客Ｇ）あの“夜の愛し仔(スレイ･ベガ)”は…
That Sleigh Beggy...
（チセ）
スレイ･ベガ…
Sleigh Beggy?
So you can see them.
（エリアス）
やっぱり見えるのかい？ それ
え… わっ 私ですか？
Y-You mean me?
You're the only one here with me.
（エリアス）
僕が今 一緒にいるのは
君しかいないだろ
名前は？
What's your name?
（チセ）チセ…
Chise.
羽鳥智世です
Hatori Chise.
My name is Elias.
（エリアス）僕はエリアス
エリアス･エインズワース
Elias Ainsworth.
よろしくね 僕の子犬(パピー)
Nice to meet you, my puppy.
It appears that you possess the sight.
（エリアス）
どうやら君は きちんと見える目を
持っているようだ
How fortunate.
運がいい
（チセ）運が… いい
Fortunate...?
She's too much of a burden to take in.
（晶子）
あんなお荷物 引き取れないわよ
（昭次）
しかし
施設へやるのも外聞がなあ…
What would people think if we
gave her to an orphanage, though?
She's being weird again.
（女性Ａ）
また変なとこ見てる　気持ち悪い
Creepy.
（少年）あの子 怖いよ
She scares me.
What a brat.
（女性Ｂ）かわいげのない子
No...
（チセ）ない…
よかったことなんて 一度もない！
I've never once been fortunate!
Then let's see to it that you feel fortunate someday.
（エリアス）
いつか 君が
よかったと思えるようにしよう
（エリアス）
実際 そんな無気力でいられると
僕が困るんだ
I can't have you being so helpless.
Dolls are fine, but I paid good money for you.
人形も悪くないけど
せっかく高値で買ったものだもの
You need to make yourself worth looking at.
（エリアス）
観察しがいのあるものじゃないと
Um...
（チセ）えっと あの…
Now, close your eyes and stand close to me.
（エリアス）
さあ 目をつぶって僕にくっついて
This may make you dizzy.
目が くらむかもよ
Nettles in the shadow...
（エリアス）影にイラクサ
Ring of holly...
ヒイラギの輪
Thoroughly entangle the branches as a spider's web.
十重(とえ)に 二十重(はたえ)に
蜘蛛(くも)の巣糸を かの枝に紡げ
Thorns?
You can open your eyes now.
（エリアス）目 開けていいよ
（エリアス）
さすがだな　ひとっ飛びだ
As expected,
we made it in one leap.
ここが僕の家
This is my home.
It's also your home, as of today.
そして
今日から君が暮らす家でもある
W-Wait a minute.
（チセ）
ちょ… ちょっと待ってください
Where are we?
ここは どこですか？
How did we get here from inside the building?
建物の中から どうやって ここに…
（エリアス）
ここはロンドンの西
イングランドの端っこの田舎
This is west of London.
A rural area on the outskirts of England.
E-E-England?
イ… イングランド？
それに 弟子って何の…
And what am I an "apprentice" of?
Oh, here.
（エリアス）ああ… ほら
You won't need that anymore.
もう それは必要ないね
You've become a mage's apprentice.
（エリアス）
君は 魔法使いの弟子になったのさ
魔法… 使い？
A mage?
（エリアス）
〝絶滅寸前〞
We're an endangered, old-fashioned kind, mind you.
〝時代遅れの〞が
付くけどね
I welcome you as my apprentice, Sleigh Beggy.
君を僕の弟子として歓迎するよ
スレイ･ベガ
いや…
Or rather... Chise.
チセ
No, no, no way...
１人でできます
お風呂くらい １人で…
I can do it myself.
I know how to take a bath.
You don't know how to use it, do you?
（エリアス）
使い勝手が分からないだろ？
Besides, you're filthy, so I'll wash you.
それに 小汚いから洗ってあげるよ
Come now.
（エリアス）
ほら 猫の子みたいに騒がないの
You're not a kitten. Stop fussing.
（チセ）ギニャアアア！
You need to soak to your
shoulders, or you'll never be warm.
（エリアス）
肩まで つかんないと
あったまらないよ
He saw everything.
（チセ）
全部 見られた…
（エリアス）あったまったら出てね
Come out when you're warm.
（チセ）
また お風呂に しっかり入れるとは
思わなかったな…
I didn't think I'd ever get a proper bath again.
（セス）
もし…
If you ever feel like giving up on life,
生きることを投げ出したいなら
あなたを欲しいと思う誰かに
あなたを預けてみますか？
why don't you try giving yourself
to someone who wants you?
（チセ）ハア…
Well, well, I thought I smelled something delicious.
（エアリエル）あらン！
何だか
おいしそうな匂いがすると思ったら
かわいい
ヒトの女の子じゃないのン！
It's an adorable human girl.
Fairies?
妖精？
あらン？ ンフッ
アタシたちは人間の言葉で言うなら
確かに妖精だけどン…
I suppose we'd be fairies, in human terms.
You better not use such unrefined words for us, though.
でも そんな無粋な言葉で呼んだら
ダメよ
そうそう！ “お隣さん”とか…
That's right!
Call us your neighbors.
“いい友達”とか
Or your good friends.
Hey, you're a Sleigh Beggy, aren't you?
（エアリエル）
ねえ あなた スレイ･ベガよねン？
スレイ･ベガを弟子にするなんて
The Thorn Mage is so silly,
taking in a Sleigh Beggy as his apprentice.
茨の魔法使いは
おかしなまねをするものねン
古(いにしえ)の金貨より
妖精の国に咲く どんな花より
Honey wine, more valuable
than gold coins of ancient times,
more precious than any flower of the land of fairies.
尊い蜂蜜酒
Adorable.
（エアリエルたち）
かわいい かわいい
アタシたちの愛し仔(ロビン)
Adorable.
Our robin.
If you're going to become a mage,
we'll give you all the help you need, my beloved.
（エアリエル）
愛するあなたが
魔法使いになるなら
アタシたちは
いくらだって
力を貸してあげるわ
ンフッ
（チセ）
愛？
Beloved?
（エリアス）チセ
Chise.
Are you all right?
大丈夫？ のぼせてない？
You're not overheated?
あっ はい 大丈夫です
Yes, I'm fine,
だから 入ってこなくて大丈夫です
so you don't need to come in.
（チセ）
あ… いない？
They're gone.
Have something to eat and drink so you can relax.
（エリアス）
とりあえず
飲んだり食べたりして落ち着いてよ
（チセ）
本当に歓迎されてるみたい
It's like they really do welcome me here.
You look like you have a lot of questions.
（エリアス）
いろいろと知りたいって顔だ
I'll try to answer your questions.
寝物語の代わりに
答えられることなら答えてあげよう
It'll be like a bedtime story.
Um, I saw fairies...
あの… さっき妖精が
（エリアス）
ああ エアリエルかな？
Ah, the ariels.
They must have greeted you.
君に挨拶に行ったんだね
あいつら 新しいものに敏感だし
They're attracted to anything new.
そうですか…
I see.
あなたが魔法使いというのは
本当ですか？
Is it true that you're a mage?
It is true.
（エリアス）本当さ
じゃあ 弟子というのは…
So when you say "apprentice"...
I mean "apprentice," my puppy.
（エリアス）
弟子は弟子だよ 僕のパピー
Sleigh Beggies are rare.
スレイ･ベガは ほとんどいないから
今日は とても幸運だったよ
I was very lucky today.
What is this "Sleigh Beggy"?
（チセ）
その“スレイ･ベガ”って
何なんですか？
If I had to choose a word, a queen bee.
（エリアス）
あえて言うなら 女王蜂かな
You—or, your kind, Sleigh Beggies,
君は… いや 君たちスレイ･ベガは
あらゆるものを引き付け
捉えることができてしまうんだ
are capable of attracting and
binding all manner of things.
Specifically, fairies and mysteries.
妖精や怪異をね
They're worker bees that are drawn to you
whether the queen bee can see them or not.
あれらは
女王蜂が見えようが見えまいが
関係なく寄る働き蜂なのさ
Even if she can't see them?
見えまいが…
（エリアス）
チセは見えるようだけど
It seems you can see them,
but that's not common among your kind.
君たちに
そういうのは まれなんだよ
そうして 女王蜂のもとに
幸福や不幸を運んでくる
They bring fortune and misfortune upon the queen bee.
（チセ）不幸も…
Misfortune?
Their kindness and favors
don't necessarily benefit a human.
（エリアス）彼らの親切と好意が
人間にとって
ためになるとは限らないから
けれど 好かれるということは
助けに困らないということでもある
However, to be loved by them means
that you'll never be without assistance.
You need their help to do magic,
so it's an important trait to have.
魔法は
彼らの助けを借りる必要があるから
とても大事な素質なんだ
君は きっと
とてもいい魔法使いになれるよ
You'll surely become a great mage.
That doesn't mean I'll be ordering you around, though.
だからって あれしろ これしろ
言う気はないけど
But I don't have any right to refuse, do I?
でも それって
はなから拒否権ないですよね？
（エリアス）ハハハ まあね
Well, no.
You're free to reconsider, though.
でも 悩んだってかまわないさ
Becoming a mage is just one path of countless many.
魔法使いだって
無数にある道のひとつ
君は もう
You're like family to me now.
家族のようなもの
なんだから
You can depend on me.
甘えてくれてかまわない
Family?
（チセ）家族…
This is an adder stone.
（エリアス）これは まじないの石
川底で自然に穴の開いたものでね
The hole formed naturally at the bottom of a river.
It'll protect you.
君を守る石だ
あげるよ
Have it.
Silver.
（エリアス）銀の君
You must be tired,
疲れたろう？ 今夜は もう お休み
so you should turn in for the day.
Would you please show her to her room?
彼女を案内してくれるかい？
I even get a proper place to sleep.
（チセ）
ちゃんとした寝床までくれた
Family...
家族…
It smells strange.
（チセ）
不思議な香り…
Is it the scent of grass?
草の匂い… かな
Chise.
（エアリエル）チセ…
チセ… チセ…
Chise.
（バン！）
（エアリエル）チセ！
Chise!
さっきの えっと… お隣さん？
You're the... um, neighbor.
Hey, why don't we go for a midnight walk?
（エアリエル）
ねえねえン
夜のお散歩に行かない？
There's a nice forest nearby.
この辺りには いい森があるのン
（チセ）でも…
But...
Come on, it'll be fine!
（エアリエル）
いいから いいから！
Just for a little bit.
ちょっとぐらい いいじゃない
Take a walk, tire yourself out a little and sleep well.
お散歩して
ちょっと疲れて ぐっすり
Let's go.
What a hopeless child.
（エリアス）しかたのない子だな
Well, it'll make for a good lesson.
まあ いい授業になるかな
It's kind of bright.
（チセ）何だか明るいね
（妖精たちの笑い声）
It's the trail we leave after we've passed by.
（エアリエル）
アタシたちの通った跡よ
チセは これも見えるのね
You can see that, too, huh?
Hey, Chise, what's your family like?
ねえ チセ 家族は？
I don't have one.
（チセ）
誰もいない
いろんな親戚に引き取られたよ
I was taken in by a lot of different relatives.
Were those people kind?
そのヒトたちは 優しかった？
Chise?
チセ？
好きになれてたら
I might not have come here if I'd come to love them.
私は今 ここに
いなかったかもしれないね
ふ〜ん
Oh?
Hey, we've walked pretty far.
ねえ… もう だいぶ歩いたよ
It's fine.
（エアリエル）大丈夫 大丈夫！
We gotta go even further, if anything.
むしろ もっと奥に行かなきゃン
あなたは…
After all, you don't need to go back anymore.
もう戻らなくたっていいんだからン
We finally duped the Thorn Mage.
（エアリエル）
せっかく茨の魔法使いを
だまくらかせたんだもの
What are you talking about?
どういうこと？
I need to take you back to our land,
or the others will get angry at me.
ちゃんと
アタシたちの国に導いてあげないと
ほかの子に怒られちゃうわン
It'll be a lot easier than living in the human world.
人の世界に暮らすよりも
ずっと楽ちんなはずだから
心配しないで
Don't worry.
Hey, it just happens to be open.
あっ ちょうど開いてる
ここから先が妖精の国
The Fairy Kingdom is past here.
A super fun world, just for you and us.
楽しい 楽しい
アタシたちとあなたの世界
（チセ）ちょ ちょっと…
W-Wait...
Let's go.
（エアリエル）行きましょう？
I-I'm going back.
も… 戻る
Oh? Back where?
（エアリエル）あらン！ どこに？
You don't even have family waiting for you.
待ってる家族もいないのに
You might as well live a happy, giddy life on this side.
だったら こっち側で
楽しく おかしく 暮らしましょう？
You're right.
（チセ）そうだね… 誰もいない
I have no one.
What's wrong, Chise?
チセ どうしたのン？
行けない
I can't.
I have to go home.
私は 帰らなきゃ
Why?
（エアリエル）どうしてン？
There's no reason you have to go back to that house.
あの家に
帰らなきゃならない理由なんて
あなたにはないでしょ？
今まで ここにいていいって
言われたことがなかった
No one ever told me that I could be there.
でも…
But that man told me...
あのヒトは言ってくれたから
Even if I'm just a toy,
おもちゃだと思ってても
飽きたら捨てられるでもいいの
even if he'll throw me out when he's bored of me,
he told me I was family, even if it was just that once.
一度だけでも…
“家族だ”って言ってくれたから
So...
（チセ）
だから…
It looks like my puppy has
already learned where her den is.
（エリアス）
僕のパピーは…
もう きちんと自分の
巣を覚えたみたいだね
Elias.
エリアス
Curses! How did you know where we were?
ソーン！
なんで ここが分かったのン
She has a collar and a bell.
（エリアス）
首輪と鈴がついてるからね
Be gone.
うせろ　今回は見逃してやる
I'll forgive you just this once.
次はサラマンダーの餌だ
Next time, you'll be salamander food.
半端者に
アタシたちのロビンを守れるかしら
Let's see if a half-baked loser
like you can protect our robin.
You don't need to remind me.
（エリアス）言われるまでもないさ
You can change your mind whenever you want, Chise.
（エアリエル）
答えは
いつでも変えていいからねン
チセ
Chise.
（エリアス）チセ
これで いい経験になっただろう？
That was a good experience, was it not?
彼らの多くは
Many of them make a habit of
seducing us with sweet words.
甘い言葉で誘惑してくる
やっかいなものなんだ
Be careful from now on.
もっと これから 気をつけなね
（チセ）ごっ ごめんなさい…
I'm... I'm sorry.
（エリアス）
いや… 僕も真っ先に
教えておくべきだったんだ
No, I should have told you right away.
（エリアス）
それが
君にとっての僕の役目なんだから
That's my duty to you, after all.
You're my apprentice.
君は もう僕の弟子なんだから
頼りなさいね
Depend on me.
（チセ）
温かい…
He's warm.
けど 何だか
こわばってるような気がする
But it seems like he's tense—
Wh-What are you doing?
（チセ）な… 何するんですか？
It's easy to get lost in the forest at night.
（エリアス）夜の森は迷いやすい
Let's go home like this.
こうやって帰ろう
To our home.
僕らの家に
We'll need to fix up your arm when we get home.
（エリアス）
帰ったら
その手を手当てしないとね
I can't have my future wife be scarred.
未来の僕の奥さんに
傷が残っちゃ大変だ
ん？ 奥さん？
Wife?
誰が 誰の？
Who is who's...
Oh, have I not told you yet?
（エリアス）
あれ？ 言ってなかったっけ
君を買ったのは もちろん
弟子にするつもりでもあるけど
I bought you to be my apprentice, of course,
but I also hope to make you my bride.
（エリアス）
僕は 君を僕の
お嫁さんにするつもりでもあるんだ
（チセ）はい？
Pardon?
To keep the seeds I tie to this branch
eda ni musubu mi ga jukusu mae ni
From falling before they ripen
ochite shimawanu you
I bloom again in profusion, painfully
kurushii hodo ni mata sakimidareru
To connect myself to tomorrow.
asa e tsunagu you
Even as they're born again
nando kurikaeshi
And again,
kurikaeshi umaretemo
I'll always show them
itsumo atarashii
A brand new sky.
sora o misete ageyou
I'll pen a story that no one,
daremo mada daremo
No one has ever written.
kaitenai monogatari
On a map so white, pure white,
shiroi masshiroi
I'll draw it out, singing it aloud.
chizu ni kaite utaou
（エリアス）
ハニームーンの準備をしようか
Shall we prepare for our honeymoon?
Huh?
A girl, departing for London with a sorcerer.
（チセ）
魔法使いと共に
ロンドンへ向かう少女
Unfamiliar towns, unfamiliar people.
見知らぬ街 見知らぬ人
The world offers a kind hand to a lonely girl, but...
孤独だった少女に
世界は優しく手を差し伸べるが…